

Ramnath K
C26, A.G.S Colony, 4th Street
Nanganallur
Chennai - 600061
Tamil Nadu





## **About Me**

# **Application Development Team Lead**

Application Development Team Lead - Front End Technologies with over 10+ years of professional experiences in User Interface Development using web technologies. Strong Developing Experience with HTML/HTML5, SCSS (CSS/CSS3) & Bootstrap Framework. Good Experience with Cross Brower Compatibility issues and Optimization for web, including CSS Sprites & best practice. Good Communication with ability to work independently or in a team environment. As Part of that i will be Develop SEO Based HTML templates. I will do performance improvements by optimizing HTML, SCSS and JavaScript's.

Also, I have Basic knowledge of Angular 6

#### **Highlights**

I have Created prototype for Existing Website which is having multiple themes. which is did like reverse operation. CSS to SCSS and HTML to Template using Twig.

Also, Setup Azure Server and Hosted with Prototype using Automated Tools like Gulp with Nodejs. Complete setup with Automated TFS Deployment. whenever the check in the prototype Changes.

Which is appreciated by Client.



# **Education**

#### **Bachelor of Computer Applications, Computer Application**

Pattammal Alagesan College of Arts & Science Completed, March 2005 Madras University 61% Kanchipuram, Tamil Nadu

#### **Master of Computer Applications, Computer Application**

Velttech Multi Tech Engineering College Completed, April 2008
Anna University 73%
Chennai, Tamil Nadu



# **Work Experience**

June 2008 - December 2010 **Web Designer** 

# Mother soft Technologies Chennai, Tamil Nadu

#### Responsibilities:

- Website Designing & Development.
- DNS Management, Website Hosting & Maintenance

December 2010 - December 2014

#### **Programmer Analyst**

Sanfive Technologies Private Ltd Chennai, Tamil Nadu

Product #1: Inventory Management System (Sanfive Technologies)

Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery & Java

Database: Microsoft SQL Server 2008

Duration: January 2011 to June 2012

Team Size: 4

Project Synopsis: The Inventory Management System was designing to make inventory management simpler and easier. This product can manage Quotations, Sales Order, Invoice Generation, Purchase Order, Goods Managing Notes and stocks in warehouses, branches and regulates all stocks movement. Transactions to receive and move stock are modeled so that you can easily create indents, purchase orders and receive orders. Accounts Management for the Concern is Completely Integrated and Fully Automated.

Responsibilities: UI Developing (HTML, CSS).

Product #2: ERP (Sanfive Technologies)

Technologies Used: Java, J2EE, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript

Database: Microsoft SQL Server 2008

Duration: August 2012 to September 2014

Team Size: 10 Project

Synopsis: ERP, It Includes Ecommerce Customer Flow For Shopping Customer Access, and Admin Flow For the Ecommerce Site, Fully Designed to Support the Customer Flow and Inventory Stock Maintenance For the Products which are Shown in Ecommerce, Order Maintenance For a Customer Ordering a Product, History Maintenance, Payment Done these are Fully Controlled From End to End and Monitored From Admin Flow, Product Dispatching Done From Admin Flow, It is Fully Automated For Multiple Organizations.

Responsibilities: Ecommerce Template UI Developing (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Angular JS).

#### **Application Development Team Lead**

Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd Chennai, Tamil Nadu

Prototyping the wireframe using Zeplin, Invission & Sympli.

CSS, JS Minification & Concatenation, Pug and Twig Template Compilation using Automated tools like Gulp & Grunt with NodeJS

Hosting Prototype using Azure Server Setup with Automated Deployment using TFS

# É

# **Training and Certifications**

Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3, Microsoft, 2017



#### **Skills**

Strong Developing Experience with HTML/HTML5, SCSS (CSS/CSS3) & Bootstrap 3 & 4 Framework.

Prototyping the wireframe using Zeplin, Invission & Sympli.

CSS, JS Minification & Concatenation, Pug and Twig Template Compilation using Automated tools like Gulp & Grunt with NodeJS



# Languages

- English ●●●
- Tamil ●●●●



## **Personal Details**

Father's Name: Mr. Krishnamoorthy Marital Status: Married Birthday: January 24, 1984 Nationality: India

Gender: Male

## **Address Details**

C26, A.G.S Colony, 4th Street Nanganallur Chennai - 600061 Tamil Nadu

#### Declaration

I, Ramnath K, hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.



	Chennai, Tamil Nadu
Ramnath K	August 22, 2018